AKASH SARKAR

ANDROID DEVELOPER



+91 7838902089

akash.sarkar188@gmail.com

New Delhi

اشأا

linkedin.com/in/akashsarkar188

SKILLS

- Java, Kotlin, Dart, Python
- · Android App Development, Flutter
- Git, SQL, Postman
- Firebase, REST APIs, Room DB
- MVVM, MVC Architecture
- Coroutines, Work Manager, Services,
 Jetpack components, Hilt, Alarm,
 Maps, Location, Camera

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY - CSE

Delhi Technical Campus

2016 - 2020

SENIOR SECONDARY - SCIENCE

Kendriya Vidyalaya Janakpuri

2015 - 2016

SECONDARY

Kendriya Vidyalaya Janakpuri

2013 - 2014

PROJECTS

ASPIRE BUDGETING

aspirebudgetmobile.app/

CORONA TRACKER

github.com/PsychoDevs69/CoronaTracker

PROFILE

A dedicated developer with a product mindset and a team player experienced in solving problems, making efficient and scalable apps, improving performance and driving product growth. Currently having 3.5 years of experience; Hunting for exceptional career opportunities!

EXPERIENCE

ANDROID DEVELOPER

SalaryBox (1M+ App downloads)

May 2021 - Nov 2023

- Implemented Live tracking, payment gateway, geofencing, face detection, chat, card scanner and MVVM.
- Improved build time, crash-free user rate, performance, memory leaks, architecture and reduced app size and app launch time.
- Used MVVM, Kotlin, Hilt, Work Manager, Alarm Manager, Services, Coroutines, Jetpack components, Firebase, Location, Maps and Camera.

ANDROID DEVELOPER

Canticle Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Sept 2020 - April 2021

- Implemented face recognition, barcode scanner, offline attendance, attendance alarms and live tracking
- Used MVC, Services, Location, Firebase, Camera, Retrofit and SQLite

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Achiredo Technologies LLP

Jan 2020 - Sept 2020

- Improved existing app by refactoring live location, bike booking, servicing and analytics screen
- Used MVC, Location, Retrofit, Firebase, Barcode scanner and Graphs

ANDROID DEVELOPER

Ghar Pe Shiksha

Jun 2019 - Dec 2019

- Developed tutor and student app from scratch by implementing chatbot, fragment architecture and dynamic forms.
- Improved architecture. Used Retrofit, Fragments, Volley and Firebase.